麥迪森 威斯康辛州
1969年10月20日
簡!
Jane!
簡 是我 開門
Jane, it's me! Open up
你有沒有告訴別人了
Did you tell anyone?
我什麼
Did I...
名字
About the name. The name?
告訴瑞克了 他覺得很好笑
Yeah, I told Rick. He thought it was funny
只有瑞克 沒有別人嗎
Just Rick and nobody else?
沒了
No
怎麼了
Why, what's the matter?
拉裡 什麼事啊
Larry, what's wrong?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry
你不知道我有多抱歉
You have no idea how sorry I am
拉裡 你嚇到我了
Larry, you're scaring me
你要幹什麼
What are you doing?
瑞克!
Rick!
Ricky!
瑞克 那名字
Rick, the name!
簡!
Janey!
有沒有告訴其他人 任何人
Did you tell anyone? Anyone!
拉裡 求求你 我...
Larry, please, please! I...
瑞克 他來了
Rick, he's coming!
那個名字
The name!
吉塞爾 我告訴吉塞爾了
Giselle. I told Giselle!
我會阻止你的
I'm going to stop you!
吉塞爾!
Giselle!
拉裡... - 媽媽!
Larry... - Mom!
你告訴誰了
Who did you tell?
吉塞爾 他殺了人了
He killed them!
別想
Don't think it
媽媽 快 - 別說
Mom, come on! - Don't say it
別想 別說
Don't think it. Don't say it
吉塞爾! 你說了那名字嗎
Giselle! Did you say the name?
別想 別說
Don't think it. Don't say it
別說
Don't say it
那個名字你告訴誰了 吉塞爾?
Who did you say the name to, Giselle?
你到底在...
What the hell are you...
拉裡!
Larry!
送葬人
*原創翻譯:微博@電燈泡diandp*
還好嗎 花花公子
What's up, playboy?
咋樣 - 不錯
How's it going? Good
今天是個好日子
Today is a good day
你有鑰匙嗎 - 沒有 鑰匙就在墊子下
You got the key? No, it's under the mat
走吧
Oh! Come on
只剩20分鐘了
It's only 20 minutes
那房子他第一次租掉 房東說房子很奇妙
This is the first time he's rented the place. The guy says it's fantastic
不然還能說什麼 "一間狗屋"?
What else would he say, "It's a dog house"?
我說服她去一下 走吧 一起去
No, I'm trying to convince her, let's go. Come on, man, work with me
薩沙 - 我很樂意去
Sash? - Yeah. I'm up for it
有點嚇人 是吧
It's a little creepy. Right?
沒有 就是天太冷而已
Nah, it's just cold
供暖關了
Heat's off
我去撒尿 像匹賽馬
(賽前喂大量水 衝刺終點為撒尿)
I've got to piss like a race horse
贊
Cute
兄弟 這地方可以
Dude, this place is sweet, bro
怎樣
Right?
桌子放那邊
We could put the desk over there
床放這裡
We could put the bed here
那得首先有床
Well, maybe if there was a bed
本來房東說帶傢俱的
I know, the landlord said it was fully furnished
小艾 快下來看啊 瘋了
Yo, El, come and check this out, man. This is crazy
快下來
Come on down
小艾 進來
Yo, El, come in here, man
宿舍裡絕對不能掛這玩意吧
See, you can't get this in the dorms, right?
夠經典
Now, that's classic
約翰 你覺得薩莎喜歡假貨 還是真貨?
John, you really think Sasha wants to see that, or that?
你把樓上弄的女性化一點吧?
You got the whole upstairs to make girly, okay?
我絕對見過更大只的 - 你狠
I've definitely seen bigger. See? You're awesome
算她狠
Bro, she's awesome, man
你倆小時候肯定老歡鬧了
Oh, yeah, you guys must've been hilarious when you were young
只有小時候嗎? 現在也是
"Must've been"? Are
頭牌
Tier 1
他襯托我聰明 而我襯托他難看
Hey, he made me look smart, and I made him look ugly
車禍之後 他一直照顧我
But after the crash, he took care of me
對我兄弟出言不遜的人 他就死定了
Talk shit about my boy's folks, you're done
如果你們兩個頭牌好了
Okay, when the Tier 1s are both ready
馬上幫我清理一下房子 還有煮飯
to cook and clean and help me do this place up right
我沒想做你倆的保姆
'Cause I'm not going to be your guys' maid
當然不做 我告訴他了的?
Of course not. I told him. Right?
你還沒吃過我做的奶油義大利面
Well, I never cooked you my butter pasta-nette
那算得上什麼
That is not a thing
因為是我獨創的
That's 'cause I invented it. Okay
還有打掃這事
And I clean, too
我包了
I promise
這幹什麼用的?
Yo, what does this do?
那你煮飯
Yeah, you cook
煮飯就煮飯 但烤爐我不管
Yes, I cook, okay? I don't bake
找到傢俱了
Found the furniture
聽說你女人太多
I've heard about you and all the girls
所以我們才必須搬出宿舍
And that's exactly why we need to get out of the dorms
這裡太好了
This is perfect
慢點走
Whoa. Easy
還好嗎
You all right?
還好 多謝
Yeah, thanks
看來房東沒騙人
So, it looks like the landlord wasn't lying
妹的
Damn, son
這我喜歡
Hey, I like this
擦
Ow. Fuck
怎樣
So?
你想不想住?
Don't you want to?
想啊 我知道你...
Well, yeah, yeah. I do. Now I know you...
所有盤子都有了 還挺乾淨
Yo, all the dishes in here, they're white
所以說
Just saying
他手腳就是閒不住
He touches everything
你定吧 小熊
It's up to you, Bear
我一個人搞不定房租 雖然你行 但我不...
I can't afford it without him. I know you can, but I don't...
艾略特 艾略特
Elliot. Elliot
就這麼定了
Yeah? We're doing it. Obviously
好嗎? - 好
Yeah? Yeah
她同意了
I see she approves, huh?
要幫忙嗎 - 不用 我搞定
Hey, you need a hand? No, I got this
別砸到自己 - 譬如去健身房了
Okay, don't break yourself. Better than going to the gym, right?
艾略特? - 幹嘛
Hey, Elliot? Yeah?
有沒有聽到砰砰聲? - 有啊
Hey, did you hear that banging? Yeah
散熱片有點問題
The radiators sound worse
小熊 找到了
Okay, Bear, here it is
里爾克說:  硬幣的兩面性代表運氣的好壞
Rilke says, "Coins symbolize the wonder and terror of fortune
你摔跤的時候 臉朝上還是朝下?
"Do you land face up or face down in the dirt?
你將會出生在哪一個家庭?
"What home will you be born into?
你會與誰戀愛?
"With whom will you fall in love?
運氣就像上帝拋硬幣
"Fortune is truly like a coin tossed by the hand of God."
我累了
I'm wiped
謝謝幫我找到引文了
Thanks for finding me that quote
想看點傻傻的東西嗎?
You wanna watch something stupid?
嗯
Mmm-hmm
就我們 好的
Just us,yeah
我去刷牙
I'm gonna brush my teeth
床上是什麼
Hey, what's on the bed?
你像是70年代的模特
"You look like a model from the '70s
或者007大反派的私人飛行員
"The personal pilot of a James Bond villain
或者19歲的考拉小熊人
"A 19-year-old koala bear person."
你若符合以上條件 我才不要你
"if any of them were true, I wouldn't have you
但你沒有一樣符合 所以我要你
"But they're not, and I do
好奇妙
"Amazingly
閒話少扯 我從未想過會遇見
"Bullshit aside, I never thought I would meet,
把孤單放一邊 佳人如你
"let alone be with, anyone like you
致我的最最愛
"With so much love,
你的騎士 你的情聖兼新室友 艾略特
"Your Knight, Beau, Casanova and new roommate, Elliot
沒有動物因製作本卡而受傷
"No animals were harmed in the making of this card!"
艾略特 這不好玩
Hey, Elliot, that's not funny!
艾略特?
Elliot?
怎麼了
What's wrong?
近來可好?
What's up, man?
小弟還好嗎
Oh, Little brother! How's it going?
看這地方 太好了
Look at this place. Fantastic
嗨 達令
Hi, darling. Hey
嗨 艾略特小叔!
Hi, Uncle Elliot!
嘿 愛麗絲侄女
Hey, Niece Alice! Hey, hey
你好
Hey, there. Hey
不好意思我們來早了 你哥的老毛病
Sorry we're so early, your brother's pathological
這叫有條不紊 專業素養
It's called being prompt and professional
維吉爾最厲害了 - 謝謝
Virgil's awesome. Thank you
我差點忘了
Oh, hey, I almost forgot
你的喬遷禮物
Here's your housewarming present
你幫我一起喝嗎
You going to help me drink it?
不要
No!
看啊
Look at this
校外租屋 約翰 亨利和你的同居女友三人行
So, a house off-campus with John Henry and a live-in girlfriend
你準備好了嗎
You ready for this?
她老厲害了 維吉爾
She's the one, Virgil
全都是她自己來的
She did all this herself
那挺好 你可以...乖巧點
That's great, it's just, you know... Be smart
學生時代就做學生
Be a student, man
這是你最後無需擔負責任的時光 享樂先
It's the last time to have no responsibilities. Enjoy it
這我不需要 我需要你那樣的生活
I don't want that. I want what you have
迷人的老婆 迷人的女兒
An amazing wife, an amazing daughter
人生何必太匆匆
Well, just don't rush it
外面的世界很精彩
That's all out there waiting for you
相信我 雖然我擁有的一切很棒
Believe me, what I have is great. It is
但我更念舊
But I missed out on all this
跳級生在大學並沒有什麼優勢
(因為比同齡女生小太多 不可能"性福")
I mean, what a college edu-ma-cation could have done for me
你有獎學金
You have a scholarship, man
你現在應該在樓上學習
You should be upstairs studying right now
你還真不吃醋
Jesus. It's a good thing you're not jealous
不挺好麼
It is good
你來試試
Come on, man, you got this. You got this!
看你的
Come on, come on, come on. Come on
哈哈
All right, all right
寶貝兒
Baby!
謝謝! 謝謝!
Barn! Thank you! Thank you!
一枚古金幣
An oldy-old gold coin, huh?
我把它放回床邊小桌了
Yeah, I put it back on the little table next to the bed
我不想留著
I didn't want to keep it
因為你是最好 最誠實
It's 'cause you're the best, most honest,
最聰明 最可愛 最重 最老的人
smartest, cutest, heaviest, oldest person here
我才不是這裡最重 最老的人
I'm not the heaviest, or the oldest
爸爸才是最老的人 還最重
Dad's the oldest and he's the heaviest
什麼
What?
她又背叛我
She ratted me out
那麼
Here
頂頂頭
Head-bump
頂頂拳
Fist-bump
那是約翰的房間 我們在樓上
That's John's room, we're upstairs
我們要走了
All right, we're out of here
派對不錯
Buddy, great party
好好的
Be good
再見 大家 再見 愛麗絲
Bye, guys. Bye, Alice
金柏莉? 我們一起文學課的
Kim? She's in my Lit class
房子裡戴帽子的女生有問題吧
Girls who wear hats inside are crazy, you know that, right?
她要在所有人離開後 做靈媒淨化
She's going to do a psychic cleansing after everyone leaves
那也要我離開嗎? - 不要
Cool, can I leave, too? No
就是燒點鼠尾草什麼的 安啦
She's just gonna burn some sage, and you are going to be nice
也許你也戴頂帽子
Maybe you need a hat
這是用扭的
It's a twist-off
謝了
Oh, thank you
約翰 你覺得這房子詭異嗎
John, do you think this house is creepy?
我不覺得 因為我不是女生
I don't, but I'm not a girl
你最好穿戴整齊 棒球開打了
And I think you should get dressed, 'cause we're playing baseball
為什麼校隊生就該陪練 哪怕在派對?
Why do jocks always have to play games, even at a party?
別想 別說
"Don't think it. Don't say it
別說 別想
"Don't say it. Don't think it."
薩莎小姐 請步上本壘
Miss Sasha steps up to the plate
她要來個長打
She's going long! She's going long!
開球吧
Okay, all right, all right. You got this?
來吧
All right
贊啦
Oh! Yes!
你們還好吧
Oh, you all right? Yeah
你喝醉了
You're drunk
你覺得有異響 還有什麼
So, you thought there were sounds and what?
不和諧的共振? - 對
"Bad vibrations"? Yeah
既然問題解決了 還有什麼大不了的?
And now if they're gone, then what's the big deal?
那些惡物都被焚燒殆盡了吧
We burned all that bad shit away, right?
那可好得緊
That's tight
你真的是靈媒?
You're actually psychic?
敏感 按我母親的說法
Sensitive, my mother says
敏感?
Oh, "Sensitive," huh?
比如你小時候 你媽在樓下對著你雙眼戳火
So, what, your mom looked you under the stairs when you were a kid?
你想用刀扔她
You shoot knives at her
對 當然不
Yeah. No
但我能感知
But I could find stuff
比如知道今天誰正往我家來
I always knew when people were coming over to the house
那你知道我腦袋裡現在想什麼?
You know what I'm thinking?
這我做得到
Yes. I might just do that
哎 你還真是靈媒
Damn, you are psychic
你那話兒挺敏感
Sensitive there, for sure
艾略特... 沒關係 薩莎
Elliot... It's okay, Sasha
我這一生一直被人們懷疑
People have doubted me my whole life
艾略特  你可以繼續活在...
Elliot, you can go ahead
活在一具安逸而膚淺的身體驅殼內
and live a sheltered, shallow, physical existence
缺了這件軀殼還真是不可耐
Well, a non-physical existence would be kind of tough
亞里斯多德想表達的意思是
What Aristotle is trying to say is...
證據為王
Well, he needs proof
這算過分嗎
Yeah, is that crazy?
我們先深呼吸
Okay, let's just take some deep breaths
OK
Okay-
如果什麼都沒發生 那是不是我該相信
So, if nothing happens, I should believe, 'cause it means
你把幽靈趕走了
you got rid of the spirit
艾略特 拜託 - 幹嘛
Elliot, come on. What?
都知道你不太信鬼神
We all know you don't believe in this stuff, okay?
但拜託你先讓她弄完吧?
But can you just please let her do it?
好的 抱歉 該有理性
Right. Sorry. No being rational
完成先
I give over. I do
小艾 你先松鬆手
Yo, El, just loosen up the grip a little bit,
我要專注調勻呼吸
I'm trying to concentrate on my breathing
好了沒有 女士們
Are you ready, ladies?
好了 開始吧
Okay, let's do this thing. Come on
並非我的自我意識 但我確實有感覺了
Now, I have no ego about it, but I do know this stuff
OK 酷 你都知道什麼
Okay, cool. Well, what do you know?
OK
Okay-
你父母死于車禍
I know your parents died in a crash
老兄
Dude...
不是他告訴我的
He didn't tell me
是你父母雙親
They did
兄弟 我什麼都沒有說過 發誓
Bro, I didn't say anything. Swear
這事我對誰也沒說過
I would never tell anyone that
他們還是很擔心你
They're worried about you, though
抱歉 我剛才笑你了 絕不是取笑
All right, I'm sorry I laughed at you before, but that's not funny
我不是來搞笑的 艾略特 這些都是我剛才得到的訊息
I'm not being funny, Elliot. This is just what I'm getting
OK 他們具體是怎麼死的?
Okay, how did they die?
是哪種類型的意外呢
What kind of accident was it?
你哥哥將竭盡所能保護你
Your brother will do anything in his power to protect you now
但你父母擔心你哥哥承受太多
But they worry that he's taking on too much
好吧 那意思你今晚已經和我哥談過了
All right. So, you talked to my brother tonight
薩莎 你的...
Sasha, your...
你奶奶會做餅乾 做麵包卷什麼的
Your grandmother has some biscuits or rolls or something
奶奶招牌麵包卷?
Gam's Rolls?
做奶奶的 都會烘培餅乾
Come on, everybody's grandma bakes biscuits
他這句話有道理
Yeah. He's not wrong about that
這個...你懂的
This is... This is... You know what?
你不如蒙住我眼睛吧
You want to blindfold me, too?
稍等片刻
Just hang on
我來幫你蒙吧
I'll take you up on that, though
我尤其善於蒙眼
I'm all down for the blindfolding,
綁其他什麼的也拿手... - 那好
whatever you got... Of course
OK 我藏了什麼 藏在哪裡?
Okay, what'd I hide? Where'd I hide it?
拜託了 別過分了 艾略特...
Oh, come on. That's crazy. Elliot...
噓
Shh
知道嗎 我...
You know what? I...
我不太喜歡這樣
I don't like this
我不想再繼續了
Yeah, I don't want to do this anymore
也許這是個糟糕的點子
Maybe this was a bad idea
得了
Nah, come on
我承認你是個騙子好手
You're a good faker, I admit it
你把鑰匙放在烤爐上的鐵盒裡
You put the keys in a pot on the stove
有沒有?
Did you?
被你聽見了
You heard
你剛才豎著耳朵聽到了吧?
You were listening for it, weren't you?
我什麼都沒聽到 你呢?
Well, I didn't hear that, did you?
沒有
No
有東西來了 - 什麼
Something's coming - What?
他們說
They're saying,
別...
"Don't...
別想
"Don't think it
別說
"Don't say it
別說 別想
"Don't say it. Don't think it
別說! 別想!
"Don't say it! Don't think it!
別說! 別想! 別說! 別想!
"Don't say it! Don't think it! Don't say it! Don't think it!
別說! 別想!
"Don't say it! Don't think it!"
別說 別想什麼東西?
Don't say or think what?
送葬人
The Bye Bye Man
上帝 搞什麼啊
Jesus! What the fuck?
金柏莉!上帝
Kim! Oh, my God
剛才怎麼了? 金柏莉? 金柏莉?
What happened, Kim? Kim?
你還好吧
Are you all right?
抱歉 - 你在幹嘛?
Sorry. What are you doing?
沒什麼 抱歉
Nothing. Nothing. Sorry
你病了嗎?
Are you sick?
晚安 愛你
Good night. Love you
我愛你 約翰(女主喊的是約翰)
I love you, John
你說啥?
What?
你是不是開玩笑的?
Hey. You're joking, right?
薩莎 你是在開玩笑吧
Sasha, you're kidding, right?
那
What?
這到底怎麼個意思
What the hell is that?
快點
Come on!
約翰 來呀
John, let's go!
我正在嘗試...
Look, I'm trying...
這樣好嗎
Like this?
噓
Shh
你在幹嘛?你聽見了嗎?
What are you doing? Do you hear that?
那到底是什麼?
What the hell is that?
可以了嗎?
You ready?
多謝你昨晚非常體貼
Thanks for being nice to me last night
好瘋狂
That was pretty crazy
絕對的
It was. Definitely
進屋坐一會兒嗎?
You want to go inside?
我室友的車沒回來
My roommate's car isn't here
我們可以再試一次
We could try again
這種事偶爾也會發生吧?
These things happen, right?
其實 不單對我 常人也會
Actually, not to me, they don't
嗯
Yeah
其實 我也一樣
Actually, not to me, either
男人沒完事兒 我之前可從沒遇到過
A guy not finishing up, I've never had that happen before
走吧
Come on
我餓了
I'm hungry
上帝
Jesus
怎麼了
What?
沒什麼
Nothing
沒什麼 OK?
Nothing, okay?
金柏莉 我得走了
Kim, I need to go
就現在
Now
擦
Fuck
兄弟 快來看看
Dude, check this out
這是舊痕跡吧
They were already there, right?
不是
No
是科林或者幾個腦殘昨晚弄的
It was Colin or one of those douches from last night
不是 我聽到有動靜
No, listen, I heard it
是在派對結束後 外面有抓撓聲
I heard something after the party outside, scratching
聽到有動靜是幾個意思?
What do you mean, you heard something?
早
Morning
你純潔又漂亮
See, you are clean and beautiful
真好
That's nice
幾個意思?
What was that?
約翰 你開車送金柏莉回家了? - 對
John, you drive Kim home? Yeah
我現在必須洗掉她的味道
And now I gotta wash her off
那女生好噁心 真的是豬
The girl's gross, man. Total pig
你這麼說不太好吧 別這麼說
Come on, man, that's not cool. Don't say that
你說的倒是輕巧
Oh, sure, yeah, it's easy for you to say
你女朋友完美無缺
Your girlfriend is perfect
上帝
Oh, God
你還好嗎?
You Okay?
不知道 也許不應該在這麼冷的天氣裡玩棒球
I don't know, maybe I shouldn't be playing baseball in the cold
也許是酗酒後遺症
That's the problem with being an alcoholic
閉嘴吧你 我還沒喝到那種程度
Oh, shut up, I didn't even drink that much
也許是我搞錯了
Maybe that was the mistake
我替你泡壺茶
I'll make you some tea
來吧
Come on
去他的
Fuck him
小熊 你剛才走神了
Bear, you went away there for a second
有嗎?
I did?
你神遊到哪裡去了?
Yeah. Where'd you go?
上帝啊 你在發抖
God, you're shivering
我在想
I was just thinking
想約翰?
About John?
不 小弟 沒事
No, little brother, it's cool
你可以隨時隨地打我電話
You can call me any time, you know that
你真的負擔很重嗎?
Are you really taking on too much?
你是不是為了保護我負擔太重?
Are you worried about protecting me?
怎麼了?
What is going on?
是因為薩莎?
Is it Sasha?
她病得很重 擔驚受怕
Yeah, she's been really sick and scared
約翰也表現怪異
And John's been acting weird
你們這幾個人只有你還正常點
You guys seemed like you were great
之前算正常嗎? 你不是看見他們跳舞了
Were we? You saw them dancing together
告訴我 到底怎麼了?
Talk to me, buddy, what's going on?
艾略特?
Elliot?
啥?
What?
明天吃個午飯什麼的
You wanna go get lunch tomorrow or something,
我們再談談?
we'll talk about this then?
我必須掛了
You know what, listen, I gotta go
我必須要...
There's something I gotta...
我有事情要處理
I gotta deal with something
艾...
El...
夥計們
Guys?
夥計們 你們在上面幹嘛?
Guys, what are you doing up there?
喂?下麵有人嗎?
Hello? Anyone down there?
喂
Hello?
夥計們! 救命!
Guys! Help!
不
No!
夥計們!
Guys!
你幹嘛啊 艾略特?
What are you doing, Elliot?
你們一直都在? - 對
You were here the whole time? Yes
胡扯
That's bullshit
那我們確實在 艾略特
But we were, Elliot
你們沒有回應我
You didn't answer me
我沒有聽到你 - 那你們在幹嘛?
We didn't hear you! What were you doing?
學習 交談
Studying, talking...
你有沒有聽到我?- 我們什麼都沒有幹
You didn't hear me? You didn't hear me? We weren't doing anything
艾略特 最後一次說 我們不可能那樣對你
Elliot, for the last time, bro, we wouldn't do that to you!
你們為什麼要騙我?
Why are you lying to me?
我們沒有 上帝
We're not! Jesus Christ
那剛才是怎麼一回事?
Then what just happened, huh?
這麼大的聲音
And there were sounds... I mean, come on!
我跟你說過這裡有異樣
I told you there was something happening
現在你相信我了吧
Now do you believe me?
別擔心 OK?
Hey, don't worry, okay?
你幹什麼?別那麼做
What are you doing? Don't do that
不要做什麼? - 不要...
Don't do what? Don't...
艾略特... - 不要碰到她
Elliot... No,no,no. Don't touch her
什麼 - 別碰她
What? Don't touch her!
你得妄想症了吧 兄弟
You are a crazy paranoid, bro!
你現在有點發燒
Yeah, you're a little warm
你和約翰之間沒有事
Okay, so you weren't with John
那我所聽到和看到又是怎麼回事?
Am I hearing things? Am I seeing things?
今天晚上你以為房子裡沒人 其實我們都在
Tonight you thought the house was empty when we were here
你走神了 艾略特
You went away, Elliot
我之前不是也走神了嗎?
I kind of went away, too
啥呀?
What?
我本來坐下來看書的...
I sat down to study...
這些圖畫我都不記得
I don't remember doing any of that
似乎現在我知道他的名字
It's like now that I know his name,
他朝著我來
he's coming for me
我越想從腦海裡除掉它 反而越來越巨大
And the more I try to get rid of it, the bigger it gets
太恐怖了
It's horrible
寶貝
Hey,babe
送葬人不是真的
Bye Bye Man's not real
它只是我們的想像
It's just something that's in our heads
是真的
That's real
我思故我在
Ideas are real
否則
If it's not,
艾略特 我們就是同時失去理智
then, Elliot, we're all losing our minds at the same time
這得多大的概率啊
And what are the chances of that?
那是什麼鬼東西? - 你說什麼?
What the hell is that? What is it?
啊
What...
艾略特 這裡什麼都沒有
Elliot, there's nothing here
你不會遲到吧!
So, you're not going to be late, right?
不會 我兩點準時到原來的停車處
No, I'll meet you at 2:00 sharp, right where we parked
我必須瞭解這事的真實程度 那個名字...
I'm going to find out how real this thing is. The name...
你是不是要和房東說一下傢俱問題?
You're going to talk to the landlord about the furniture?
還有房子
And the house
也許他能找找別的房子
Maybe he can find somewhere else
你現在感覺好點了嗎?
You're feeling better, though?
也許吧
I guess
大白天的 沒什麼可怕
It's hard to be scared in the middle of the day
我會照顧好你
I'm going to take care of you
天哪
Oh, my God
你在發抖
You're shivering
我答應你一定搞定這事情
I'm going to figure this out, I promise
我們兩點見
I'll see you at 2:00
我愛你!
I love you
*搜索:送葬人
*搜索結果: 0匹配
*搜索:布坎南 威廉姆斯 圖書館
*搜索結果: 128匹配
*圖書館資料庫 搜索:送葬人
*匹配: 0
*圖書館資料庫 搜索:別想 別說
*返回一條結果:
註冊檔案 作廢檔69號 作者雷德曼
"Register Archive. Dead File 69. Redmon."
拿去戴上
Here, put these on
有必要嗎?- 有
Really? - Yeah
這些都是原件 我們不想...
They're originals and we don't want
你的手汗汙損文件
your sweaty palms messing up the documents in the box
作廢文件有作廢的規定
Now, the dead file has dead articles,
不能出版的材料都必須銷毀
material that got killed before going to press,
但為了將來考慮而留存一份 作者雷德曼
but still saved for posterity. And it was written by Redmon
多謝
Thanks. Mmm-hmm
謝謝 鄧尼斯
Thank you, Dennis
戴先生?  - 是我 有何貴幹嗎?
Mr. Daizy? Yes, how are you doing?
其實不是什麼大事
Not so great, actually
我和我的朋友們
Uh, me and my friends
租了你的房子
are renting your place
奧克戴爾市 森普雷裡鎮 37號
out in Sun Prairie. 37 Oakdale
這是兩個帥小夥子
Oh, yeah, the two handsome guys
你和他們一起的嗎?
Are you with them?
你那個房子很怪 戴先生
You have a weird house, Mr. Daizy
真的太可怕了
Really, it's awful
很對不起 不過他們已經簽了租約
Well, I'm sorry that you feel that way, but they did sign a lease
保佑你
Bless you
抱歉
Sorry
你還好嗎? - 這裡好冷
You okay? It's really cold in here
這裡是暖棚 完全不冷 甜心
It's a hothouse. It's actually not cold at all, honey
也許你該在家裡床上躺著
Maybe you should be home in bed?
戴先生
Look, Mr. Daizy
地下室裡有一個舊的床頭櫃
There was an old nightstand in the basement
裡面有文字
And it has this writing inside it
是從哪裡來的?
Where did it come from?
床頭櫃?
A nightstand?
我們從這堵牆說起
Let's begin by considering this wall...
我們都同意以下命題...
Now, we can all agree that the sentence...
抱歉 - 找座位坐下
Sorry. Yeah, have a seat
我們同意以下命題
Now, we can all agree that this sentence,
"這是一座牆" 此句是一個真實的表述
"This is a wall," is a truth claim
牆是真實存在的 我看見了 你也看見了
This wall is real. I see it, you see it
大家都能觸摸到
We can touch it
比如 我擦掉這堵牆上的幾個原子
Likewise, if I were to brush a few atoms from this wall,
它仍舊還在 它仍舊站在我們面前
it would still be here. It would still be here before us
牆還是那堵牆
It would still be "the Wall."
我如果繼續
But what if I continued
擦掉一些原子 從這堵牆上一個接一個?
to slowly brush the atoms, one by one, away from this wall?
一開始 你還會說這仍舊是堵牆
Well, at first, you'd say it's still a wall
我繼續擦掉更多 它還是一堵牆
I brush a few more, well, it's still a wall
最後我移掉了所有的原子 只留下一個
But what if I remove every single atom from this wall except for one?
你們看到我移掉每一個原子的過程
And you've seen me brush every single atom from this wall
除了那只被留下來的原子
except for that one atom,
我指著這個原子說 僅剩一粒
and I point to it, and I say, "There, that's what's left."
那就是牆
That's the wall
那麼請問
Now, is it?
它還是不是牆
Is that the wall?
搞什麼...
What the...
還好嗎 約翰?
All right, John?
歡迎回來
Welcome back
描述和現實
Language and reality
是相互作用的 在我們構思...
inform each other as we construct...
OK 我正在查找送葬人 對不對?
Okay, I'm looking up The Bye Bye Man, right?
網路上什麼都沒有 所以我鍵入
There's nothing online, so I type in,
別說  別想
"Don't say it, don't think it,"
指引我來到這裡 發現了作廢檔案 還有雷德曼
and it led me here, the dead archives and Redmon
這些都是在他的文檔裡發現的
Here's what was in his folder
我認為不停的重複寫 是為了阻止...
I think you write it and repeat it to try and keep from saying...
送葬人
The Bye Bye Man
OK  但為什麼要寫在作廢檔裡?
Okay, but why is that in the dead files?
1969年10月18日 署名 拉裡雷德曼
"October 18, 1969, byline, Larry Redmon
迪爾菲爾德 愛荷華州
"Deerfield, Iowa
某少年 被指控謀殺
"A teenager, accused of murdering
他全家及另外四名少年
"his own family and four other youths
當報告者問及動機時 原文如下
"When asked by this reporter why he would do such a thing, herephed,
'送葬人迫使我做的'
"'The Bye Bye Man made me do it."'
這文章說的是少年發瘋
It's an article about a kid who went crazy
但卻從未刊登
But it was never published
作者拉裡雷德曼
And Larry Redmon, the writer...
在當地相當有名
He was pretty infamous locally
他將這件迪爾菲爾德少年事件束之高閣後
After he killed this piece about the kid in Deerfield,
拉裡雷德曼拿著散彈槍
Larry Redmon took a shotgun
殺害了總共八名朋友或家人
and murdered eight friends and family members
就在此間的麥迪森市
right here in Madison
別說 別想 - 媽媽
Don't say it. Don't think it. Mom!
媽! - 別說 別想
Mom! Don't say it. Don't think it
別說
Don't say it
媽 關門
Mom, shut the door!
吉塞爾!你都告訴誰了
Giselle! Who did you tell?
沒有 我們誰都沒說 拉裡!
No one! We didn't tell anyone, Larry!
媽咪
Mommy!
住手
Stop!
我們誰都沒有說
We didn't tell anyone!
我發誓什麼都沒說
I swear we didn't say anything!
你走開
Get back! Please!
可能他是受自己的文字而啟發
Maybe he got inspired by what he was writing about
* 某種下水道疏通劑
你不會贏的
You won't win
不會讓你得逞
I won't let you
這案子在其他地方都沒有被提及
There are no other mentions of these cases anywhere else
就像是有人重新安排了故事 因此沒有人會讀到
It's like someone redacted the whole story, so no one else could read it
究竟誰會那麼做
Why would anyone do that?
很顯然 他是精神錯亂了
Well, obviously he was bat-shit crazy
如果你移去所有指向過去...
But, if you remove all references
的線索時候
to something in the past,
則過去也就不存在了
that past no longer exists
連思想都會消失
Even the idea of it is gone
也許有人想要送葬人永遠消失
Maybe somebody wanted to make this Bye Bye Man disappear permanently
你在這裡拿到了這最後一份記錄
And you've got the last record of it right there
我馬上回來
I'll be back
很好 還夠時間
Good, I have time
寫也別寫 白癡
Don't write it either, idiot
你在幹什麼 孩子
What are you doing, boy?
你是不是瘋了
Are you out of your mind?
我...
I, um...
你到底怎麼了 艾略特?
What is wrong with you, Elliot, huh? What the...
很抱歉我得走了 我遲到了
I'm sorry, I need to go. I'm late
艾略特!
Elliot!
上帝
Oh, my God
薩莎!
Sasha!
約翰!
Hey, John!
薩莎!
Sasha!
喂
Hello
金柏莉 是我艾略特
Kim, it's Elliot
艾略特... 天那 我剛才還在想你們呢
Elliot... God, I was just thinking about you guys
要上來嗎 - 聽我說
You wanna come up? Listen. Listen
你幹什麼了
Um, what are you doing?
你是說現在還是派對之後?
You mean, right now? Or since the party?
你就是為此而來的? - 你能下樓嗎
Isn't that why you're here? Kim, can you come down?
請你再來次降神會
I want to do another séance
就現在 我們四個人 還是那房子
Right now, with all four of us, at the house
你是對的
Listen, you were right
我搞錯了
I was wrong
好吧
Sure
我一會兒就下來
I'll be down in a sec
送葬人只存在於我找過的地方
The Bye Bye Man doesn't exist anywhere else that I could find
你不必找他 艾略特
You don't have to look for him, Elliot
他會來找我們
He's found us
你不由自主會去想他
You can't help thinking about him
你越是想起他 他越真實
And the more you think about him, the closer he gets
你看見的並不存在
You see things that aren't there
你沒看見的卻存在
You don't see things that are there
包括聽覺
Or hear things
比如硬幣旋轉的聲音 - 對
Like a coin rolling. Yeah
就像火車
Like a train
搭上它 就會傳播
Some people catch it and it spreads
一部分人會發瘋 但終究難逃一死
Some go crazy sooner, but they all die in the end
那個詞只要被傳播 他就會找上你...
The word spreads and he comes to you with...
與那些東西一齊出現
With that thing
我告訴了凱蒂
I told Katie
我也不想這麼做的
I didn't want to
但對付癌症 除了切除還能怎麼辦?
What can you do with cancer but cut it out?
必須在擴散前阻止它 以免其他細胞死亡
You have to stop it before it spreads and every cell dies
如果我們不將其切除 就會擴散到全世界
This could spread everywhere if we don't cut it out
你還告訴誰了
Did you tell anyone?
沃特金女士 圖書館理員
Ms. Watkins, the librarian
我們也必須得去她那兒
We have to get to her, too
你說必須去那兒是什麼意思
What do you mean, you have to get to her?
停車
Stop!
天那
Oh, my God!
停車! 艾略特  停車!
Stop! Elliot, stop!
我來幫你們
Let me help you!
金柏莉! 等等!
Kim! Wait!
金柏莉!
Kim!
金柏莉! 金柏莉!
Kim! Kim!
不
No!
我們必須救助他們
We have to help them!
你沒看見嗎?那一大家子人
What do you see? It's a family!
那是你頭腦想像的
It's in your head!
不 金柏莉! 有火車 真的火車
No, Kim! There's a train, a real train!
不
No!
金柏莉! 讓開 這是你的想像
Kim! Move! It's in your head!
金柏莉! 不!
Kim! No!
艾略特 發生什麼
Elliot, what happened?
金柏莉 她死了
Kim, she's dead
上帝啊
Shit. Jesus
上帝 是他幹的 他殺了她
Oh, my God. It was him. He killed her
你說的對 他要進入我們腦中
You were right, he's trying to get inside us
他進入她腦子 他會使我們瘋狂然後殺掉我們
He got in her. He's going to drive us crazy and he's going to kill us
你說的是 送... - 對
You mean the... Yeah
原因我晚點告訴你
He's why I was late to get you
他是你生病的病根
He's why you're feeling sick
你有沒有把名字告訴其他人
Have you said the name to anyone?
名字嗎...沒有
The name... No. No
那你呢
Have you?
沒有 我沒有告訴...
No, I haven't said...
千萬不要 我們絕對不可以把名字告訴任何人
Good. Don't. We can't say the name to anyone else, ever
要你對我指手畫腳?
You going to tell me what to do now?
發誓你別說這名字 以免擴散
Swear you won't say the name so we don't spread it
不會的 ... - 約翰 求你
No... - John, please
求你
Please
兄弟 發誓 - 你別再提這事好嗎
Bro, swear it. You just need to cut this shit
你發誓
You swear!
發誓 - 不
Swear! No
發誓! - 艾略特 住手
Swear! Elliot, stop it!
發誓! - 你有什麼毛病 艾略特?
Swear! What's wrong with you, Elliot?
你有什麼毛病? 艾略特 住手
What's wrong with you? Elliot, stop it!
你們都給我分開
Hey, guys! Hey, break it up!
我說現在給我分開
I said break it up right now!
退後
Back up
他進入你了是不是? - 沒人進入我
He got to you, didn't he? No one got to me, all right?
承認吧 他使得你暴怒
Admit it. He's making you feel angry
他讓你得病 - 是嗎
He's making you sick - Yeah?
他讓你瘋狂
He's making you crazy
你有所指嗎?
You on something?
沒有 我很煩躁
No, I'm upset
有點小小的意見不合
We're just having a little argument
這叫意見不合?
You call that a "little argument"?
約翰 求你
John, please
別說
Please don't say it
別說什麼
Don't say what?
薩莎? - 我不會的
Sasha? I won't
約... 你別
J, you can't
艾略特腦中叫那個名字的人很危險
This name of some stupid shit Elliot thinks is dangerous
對 我指的就是金柏莉
Yes. I was talking about Kim
她包裡有把錘子
There was a hammer in her bag
上面沾滿鮮血
It was covered with blood
天那
Oh, my God
火車司機說是你在後面追趕金柏莉
Train's engineer said that you were chasing Kim,
拿著錘子
with the hammer
司機說她哭著求救
He said she was crying for help,
她跳出你的車子 擺脫你
and that she jumped out of your car to get away from you
老天 艾略特?
Jesus Christ. Elliot?
不是這個樣子的
That's not what happened
不是?他們發現金柏莉的室友凱蒂
No? They found Kim's roommate, Katie Williams
也是被錘殺的 但是...
She was killed by a hammer, too, but...
你顯然知情 是不是
You knew that, didn't you?
薩莎 不 我當時在圖書館
I....Sasha, no! I was at the library
他讓我忘記了時間 你必須...
He made me lose track of time. You have...
薩莎?
Sasha?
你想在這裡和我說嗎
Do you want to talk to me here?
你要不要告訴我到底怎麼了?
You want to tell me what's going on?
別說 別想 你是對的!
Don't say it. Don't think it. You were right!
收聲
Quiet
薩莎 他不想你說什麼
Sasha, what doesn't he want you to say?
薩沙 - 你閉嘴
Yeah, Sash. You! Shut it!
又來了 約翰
It just happened,John
你看見嗎 又是他
You see that? It's him
沒有
No
薩莎
Sasha
怎麼回事
What? What is it?
有血
Blood
血?
Blood?
在哪?
Where?
你看見什麼了 這是他存心讓你看見的東西
What do you see? He makes you see things
慘
Fuck
上帝
Oh, my God. Hey! Hey! Hey!
退回去 你站開
Back away. I need you over here
她很好 - 旁邊呆著
She's fine. Stay back
等等 那東西來了
Wait, there he is!
老弟 有問題嗎
Hey, bud. Somethin' wrong?
抱歉 我還以為...
I'm sorry. I thought... What?
你還好嗎
Hey, are you all right?
等等 薩莎!
Wait! Wait! Sasha!
他會帶她回家
He's gonna take her home
她需要躺一會兒
and she's going to lie down for a bit
我是她男友 她需要我
I'm her boyfriend. She needs me
也許過陣子再說
Maybe. Maybe later
現在你跟我走
But right now, you're going to come with me
我們得談談
We're going to talk a little bit
你們有沒有說出名字?
Did you say the name to anyone?
她可沒有 兄弟
She didn't, man
我們都沒有
Neither of us did
別說 別想
Don't say it. Don't think it
別想 別想
Don't think it. Don't think it
對你也許是好消息
Good news for you. Maybe
金柏莉留了遺言
Kim Hines wrote a suicide note,
自認對室友之死負責
taking responsibility for her roommate
也負責你以及你家屋簷下現在活著的兩位之死
and for the deaths of you and the other two living at your house
我估計她也要殺你 按計劃
So, I guess she was planning on killing you, too
是不是正因為如此 艾略特?
Is that what happened, Elliot?
你發現了真相 所以追她
You found out and you chased her?
我覺得那不是謀殺
I don't think that's murder
別想 別說 別想
Don't think it. Don't say it. Don't think it
那你需要寫下來嗎
You want to write it?
不要
No
你是否打算告訴我 其實你早知道了
You're going to tell me, you know that
還是不知道的好
I hope not
為什麼追趕金柏莉?
Why did you chase Kim?
我說了 是想幫她
I told you, I was trying to help her
所以你把她趕向火車?
So you chased her into a train?
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
你會失去一切的
You could lose everything
獎學金 還有漂亮女朋友
Your scholarship, that pretty girl
你是聰明孩子
You are a smart kid
告訴我 我才能幫你
Talk to me and I can help you
否則我也愛莫能助
Otherwise, it'll be out of my hands
不要事後後悔
and you'll be wishing that you had
也許你才會後悔
You might find yourself wishing I hadn't
放心 後果我自負
Well, you let me worry about that
你真想知道?
You really want to know?
你真的認為真相和誠實 是最好的對策嗎
You really think the truth, honesty, is the best policy?
對 - 向來管用嗎
I do. Always?
有不管用的嗎
When wouldn't it be?
你有孩子嗎
You have kids?
也許
Maybe
你有孩子
You have kids
別想 別說
Don't think it. Don't say it
假設你目擊一次史無前例最慘烈的凶案
What if you saw the worst crime scene ever?
校園大屠殺
A mass murder at a school
屍橫遍野 肝腦塗地
With dead bodies and brains and students
鞋底全是學生們的鮮血
and sneakers with blood on them
你回家時 孩子們問你
And you go home, and your kids say,
媽媽你今天怎麼樣啊
"Tell us about your day, Mommy."
你可以推誠布公
You could be honest
告訴他們真相
You could tell the truth
描述你所看到的所有可怕噩夢
You could describe every awful nightmare thing you saw,
你腦中揮之不去的一切
and what was burned into your head
將會成為他們腦中揮之不去的一切
would be burned into their heads forever
或者
Or...
你可以緊緊擁抱他們
You could hug them tight,
將誠實的真相藏在心裡
and spare them your honest truth
你會怎麼做
What would you do?
我會擁抱他們
I'd hug them
請別讓我說
Please don't make me say it
我沒有傷害過別人
I haven't hurt anyone
但我懼怕把它引入你的腦中
But I'm afraid of putting this into your head
我所要做的就是說給你聽 你和孩子們會...
All I have to do is talk to you, and you and your kids...
全都得死
You're all dead
艾略特!
Hey! Elliot!
是你朋友死了?
Your friend died?
到底怎麼回事
What the hell is going on, man?
謝謝你保我出來 但我得走了
Thanks for coming to get me, but I gotta go
是不是薩莎和約翰...
Was it Sasha and John...
告訴我 讓我幫你
Hey, talk to me. Let me help you
無論事態如何 你都幫不上忙 OK?
Whatever is going on, there's nothing you can do, okay?
我一個字都不會告訴你的
I literally can't tell you
我不允許壞事發生在你身上 維吉爾
I'm not going to let it happen to you, Virgil
特別是你
Especially not you
你到底在說什麼
What are you talking about?
你有家室 照顧好他們
You've got a family. Go take care of them
艾略特 你就是我家人啊 艾略特!
Elliot, hey! You are my family. Elliot!
媽的
Shit!
擦
Fuck!
天那
Oh, my God
你要幹嘛 艾略特?
What are you doing, Elliot?
你什麼毛病 艾略特?
What's... What's wrong with you, Elliot?
搞...
What the...
十分抱歉
I'm so sorry
* 沃特金
艾略特?
Elliot?
嗨 沃特金女士 - 嗨 艾略特?
Hi, Ms. Watkins. Hi. Elliot?
自從上次談話後 我一直有奇怪的想法
I've been having some really strange thoughts
關於送葬人
about that Bye Bye Man since we talked
沃特金女士...
Ms. Watkins...
沃特金女士 你千萬不能對別人說
Ms. Watkins, you can't talk to anyone about it
要麼我晚點去你家
Well, maybe I can come over to your house later
我十分抱歉
I'm so sorry
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too
相信我 但是我腦中的想法太栩栩如生了
Believe me, but I've just been having the most vivid thoughts. I...
艾略特?
Elliot?
* 戴先生
* 雷德曼遺孀 太陽山路83號 床頭櫃
艾略特?
Elliot?
雷德曼...
Redmon...
拉裡雷德曼
Larry Redmon
那作家
The writer
這是他的床頭櫃
It was his nightstand
沃特金女士
Ms. Watkins
OK 我晚點和你見
Okay, maybe I'll see you later,
也許我有辦法解決一切
maybe I'll have a fix for this
我得掛了 多謝 - 不客氣
I gotta go. Thanks. Oh, you're welcome...
我一會兒到
I'll be there soon
他差點弄死我們
He almost got us, man
擦 我差點用球棍害死你 但是 他要完蛋了
Oh, fuck! I almost killed you with a bat, but, fuck, he's not going to get us
他再也無法加害我們
He's not going to get us
我有辦法了
I'll figure this out
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry, but...
抱歉 我不能叫救護車 因為你會說的
I'm sorry, I can't call an ambulance, 'cause you're gonna say it
你會說的 因為是我害你的
You will. You will. 'Cause I messed you up
我會儘快返回
I'll be back as soon as I can
這我拿走了
I'm taking this
你找到的 我現在去和她談談
You found her and now I'm going to go talk to her
我愛你
I love you
還有別碰他
And don't touch him
拜拜 幸福
Bye-bye, happiness
你好 寂寞
Hello, loneliness
我覺得我想哭
I think I'm gonna cry
拜拜 愛情
Bye-bye, love
拜拜 甜蜜愛撫
Bye-bye, sweet caress
你好 空虛
Hello, emptiness
我覺得要死了
I feel like I'm gonna die
拜拜 我的愛 再見
Bye-bye, my love, goodbye
喂
Hello?
雷德曼太太?
Mrs. Redmon?
走開
Leave
雷德曼太太?
Ms. Redmon?
我說走開 你聾了 還是傻了
I said, leave! Are you deaf, or just defective?
雷德曼太太 你丈夫之前有沒有替"登記冊"寫過稿?
(一家英國新聞網站)
Ms. Redmon, did your husband write for The Registera long time ago?
你太小 怎麼可能記得
You're too young to remember that
雷德曼太太 你還活著
Ms. Redmon. You're still alive
我知道你丈夫殺了很多人
I know your husband killed a lot of people
但我不認為他瘋了
But I don't think he was crazy
我需要你的説明 無論你記得什麼都行
I need your help, whatever you remember
關於火車 金幣
There's a train, gold coins...
獵犬
A hound...
他找上拉裡時
He came to Larry
帶著狗
With the hound
拉裡告訴我的一切讓我惡夢
What Larry told me gave me nightmares
我要他住手
I made him stop
我理解
I understand
我要你把拉裡說過的一切都告訴我
But I need you to tell me everything Larry said
求你
Please
拉裡當時在寫一篇少年殺害全家的報導
Larry was on a story of a teenager who killed his family
像狗仔隊記者一樣到處打探 聽到流言...
Poked around like a good nosy reporter and heard rumors...
關於某個惡魔的消息
Whispers about an evil,
某種死神 能令少年人瘋狂
some kind of a reaper that drove the teenager mad
拉裡四處嗅探 並記錄下來
Larry had to go nosing around and writing it down
結果拉裡引火焚身
And then it came to Larry, too,
此惡夢 此名字 我們必不能想也不能說
this nightmare, this name we must not think or say
拉裡從愛荷華州回來的第三天
But just three days after Larry got back from Iowa,
我下班回家
I came home from work
1969年10月20日
October 20th, 1969
那天起 我的生活天旋地轉
The day my life went turn-turn-turn...
別說 別想
Don't say it. Don't think it
別說 別想 別說
Don't say it. Don't think it. Don't say it
別想 別說 別想
Don't think it. Don't say it. Don't think it
別說 別想 別說 別想
Don't say it. Don't think it. Don't say it. Don't think it
別說 別想
Don't say it. Don't think it
上帝
Oh, my God
別說
Don't say it
拉裡... 上帝
Larry... Oh, my God
我只是在工作
I was just doing my job
就工作 跟蹤報導而已
That's what I do. I track down the story
我就幹了這些
And that's what I was doing
知道嗎
See...
一旦你知道他的名字 就無法擺脫他了
Once you know his name, you can't escape him
他進入你腦中
You see, he gets in your head and...
迫使你做恐怖的事情
He makes you do horrible things
OK OK
Okay. Okay
什麼恐怖的事情
What horrible things?
誰迫使你做的?你在說些什麼
Who makes you do this? What are you talking about?
你上床休息好嗎 甜心
Let's get you to bed, okay, sweetheart?
聽好了 我不知道他是死人還是活人
Listen. Listen, I didn't know if he was alive or dead
只要獵狗來了
And then the hound...
你就知道他快來了
That's how you know he's coming
看見獵狗 聽見硬幣聲
When you see the hound and you hear the coins,
便可知他在附近了
that's when you know he's close by
你懂嗎? - 不 我...
You understand? - No, I...
拉裡...
Larry...
我不懂怎麼回事 但我想...
I don't know what's happened, but I'm trying...
他會聽他的名字
He listens for his name
任何人只要說到 比如你
Anyone could say it. It could be you
比如我
Or it could be me
好比投硬幣來決定運氣
And it's just dumb luck like the flip of a coin
我聽到名字後告訴了簡
And I heard the name and I told Janey the name
別想 別說
"Don't think it. Don't say it."
這是什麼意思? 你寫的什麼文章
What does this mean? What did you write?
我不懂
I don't understand
他讓你看見幻象
He makes you see things
迫使你行動
And he makes you do things
天知道他迫使多少好人做出恐怖的事情
Who knows how many good people he's made do horrible things like this
不 上帝 不要
No! Oh, God, no! Please
請不要
Please, don't
把槍放下
Please put it down
你認為是我?
You think it's me?
是我幹的?
You think I did this?
真相是...
This is what happens
他們說人亂開槍 他們說人瘋了
They say people snap. They say people go crazy
不是 全都因為他
No, it's him
是他幹的
It's him that's doing it!
把槍放下 好嗎
Just put it... Put it down. Okay?
不
No
我愛你
I love you
其實拉裡是個英雄
But in the end, Larry was a hero
請你告訴大家
You tell people that
拉裡抹掉了他
Larry erased him, you see
他幹掉了所有知道名字的人 以免擴散
He did away with everyone who'd heard it before they could pass it on
但留下了你
But not you
你還在這裡
You're here
這次你打算怎麼活命?
How did you survive all this time?
活命? - 對
Survive? Yes
上次怎麼打敗他的
How did you beat it?
我沒有打敗他
I didn't beat it
我就不知道名字
I never knew it
什麼
What?
如果我丈夫把名字告訴我
If my husband had told me the name,
他就會像殺其他人一樣殺掉我
he'd have had to kill me with the rest
我丈夫控制住自己
My husband controlled himself
你該死的丈夫在床邊櫃裡寫滿了名字
被你賣了 恰好被我讀到
Your fucking husband wrote the name in the nightstand you sold and I read it
他打字機列印了作廢檔 恰好也被我讀到
He typed it in a dead article and I read that, too!
別說名字
Don't you say it!
你丈夫放過了你 卻害慘了我
Your husband spared you and he got me
他進入了我 進入了我的朋友們
He's in me now. He's in my friends
要我幫你嗎? - 要
You want my help? Yes
拿去
Here
殺掉所有你親自告訴過的人 然後自殺
Kill all of the ones you told first and then kill yourself
這是唯一的出路
It's the only way
不行 一定會有另外的出路
No! There has to be another way
別說 別想 這就是線索
"Don't say it. Don't think it." It's a clue
看啊
Look
上帝 他來了
Oh, my God. He's coming!
你說什麼?你又沒帶他來
What are you talking about? You didn't bring him here
你看不到嗎? - 看到什麼
Don't you see it? See what?
光線...名字...他在你腦中
The light... Hear the name... He's in your head
他編造幻象讓我們看 編造一切 讓我們恐懼
He makes us see things, hear things, tricks to make us afraid
讓我們恐懼 他就會膨脹
He makes us afraid. Then he grows
我們越恐懼 他就越真實
The more scared we are, the more real he gets
我們用恐懼製造了他
We make him real with our fear
是我們讓他更強大
We make him more powerful
我們給了他力量
Yeah, we give him the power
他就越真實 我們一想到他 他就能聽見我們
and he gets closer and he hears us when we think of him
但也許 如果我們不再恐懼 就能奪取他的力量
But maybe, if we're not afraid, we take his power
也許 我們不再恐懼 他就一無是處
Maybe, if we're not afraid, he's nothing!
你怎麼知道我的拉裡沒有嘗試過?
How could you figure it out and my Larry not?
救我
Help me!
向我開槍
Shoot me!
Shoot me now!
不 這不是真的
No, no! It's not real!
No, it's not real
救命
Help me!
這局我贏了吧
I have you now, don't I?
再玩玩別的花招啊 來呀
Come on, try another trick. Come on, try it!
你哪裡去了
Where are you?
上帝
Oh, my God
薩莎!
Sasha!
接電話
Pick up
薩莎?
Sasha?
我是薩莎 請留言...
Hey. It's Sasha. Leave a message...
你最好還沒有傷害到她
You better not fuckin' hurt her!
多謝
Thanks
薩莎 我來了
Sasha. I'm coming
雖然艱難 但別恐懼
I know it's hard, but don't be afraid
別相信所見
And don't believe anything you see
搞什麼...
Whoa, what the...
什麼?
What?
不 你不是真的
No, you're not real
果然不是真的
Not real!
我就知道
Ha! I knew it!
OK 花招而已
Okay. Tricks
你想玩花招?
You want to play tricks?
OK 我準備好了
Okay. I'm ready
艾略特!
Elliot!
約翰!
John!
你們都在哪兒 夥計們?
Where are you guys?
艾略特?
Elliot?
薩莎!
Sasha!
艾略特!
Elliot!
薩莎?
Sasha?
我在這裡
I'm in here
上帝
Oh, God
你像鬼一樣
You look like hell
上帝
Jesus
你在這裡
There you are
艾略特... 謝天謝地 你回來了
Elliot... Thank God. You're back
我沒有...
I'm not...
天
Oh, my God
怎麼了
Hey, what's the matter?
艾略特 你幹嘛啊
Elliot, what are you doing?
啊
Shit
走開
Get away
好了 一切都會沒事的
Hey, come on, it's all going to be okay
我們會好好的 我好點了
We're going to be okay. I feel better
走開
Get away!
艾略特! 是我啊
Elliot! It's me!
搞什麼鬼?
What the hell?
艾略特 我不懂你在幹嘛
Elliot, I don't understand. What are you doing?
救命
Help!
艾略特! 行了啦
Elliot! Come on
來吧 約翰
Come here, John
求你 艾略特! - 救命
Please, Elliot! Help!
我搞不懂 求你
I don't understand. Please
不
No
來吧 - 不
Come on. No!
求你
Please
停下 艾略特 請你停下你停一下好嗎
Stop. Elliot, please stop! Will you just stop?
別靠近我
Get away from me!
Get away!
夥計們!
Guys!
薩莎  約翰 都是花招 不是真的
Sasha, John, it's a trick. It's not real
聽我說
Listen to me!
薩莎 約翰 聽我說 那不是真的
Sasha,John. Listen to me, it's not real
約翰 不
John,no!
艾略特! 開槍! 開槍!
Elliot! Shoot! Shoot!
不
No!
來吧 殺了我
Go ahead. Kill me
你贏了
You win
不
No
你放過他們!
You leave them alone!
快開門 外面凍死了
Come on, guys. It's freezing out here
有沒有人在家
Hey, man. Anybody home?
愛麗絲也在 她來給你加油
I've got Alice here. She's here to cheer you up, buddy
艾略特!不
Elliot! No!
有沒有在家
Hey! Anybody home?
夥計們 我知道你們在裡面
Guys, come on! We know you're in there
我聽到聲音 喂
I hear something. Hello!
開開門 夥計們 我們快變成冰棒啦
Open the door, you guys. We're turning into popsicles out here
快走! 艾略特?
Go away! Elliot?
走開!
Go away!
我們哪裡也不去 艾略特
No, no. We're not going anywhere, Elliot
小叔 開門!
Uncle, open up!
請你們兩個離開這裡 必須走
Please, get her out of here. Both of you, you need to go!
艾略特 快開門 否則我報警了
Elliot, open the goddamn door or I'm calling the police
那好 報警
Good. Do it!
甜心 你去車裡等著
Honey, why don't you go wait in the truck?
不 爸爸 我要小便
No! Daddy, I got to pee!
上車去 快
Go to the truck, please
開門 老弟 快點
Open the door, man, come on
走啊
Go. Go
艾略特! 拜... 拜...
Elliot! Bye... Bye...
不
No!
艾略特 到底怎麼回事
Elliot, what the hell is going on?
維吉爾 快讓她出去
Virgil, please, get her out of here
艾略特小叔!
Uncle Elliot!
OK 花生米 聽好我 OK?
Okay, Peanut, I need you to listen to me, okay?
我要你去車上
I need you to go to the truck
不 爸爸 我要去...
No, Daddy, I got to 90!
去邊上我能看見你的地方 速度 OK?
Go someplace close where I can see ya, and be quick, okay?
露天?
Outside?
又沒人看的 寶貝 沒事
No one is going to see you, baby. It's okay
去吧
Go.Go.Go
艾略特 艾略特 裡面怎麼回事?
Elliot. Elliot, what is going on in there?
別想 別說 別想 別說
Don't think it. Don't say it. Don't think it. Don't say it
艾略特 你在說什麼? 什麼啊?
Elliot, what are you saying? What?
我必須這麼做 我沒瘋
I have to do this. I'm not crazy
讓我幫你
Let me help you
你不行的 但我能幫你 只要你走
No, you can't. But I can help you, if you go!
但是你不能在邊上看著
But I'm not going to let you catch it!
拜... 別說! 別想!
Bye... Don't say it! Don't think it!
什麼? 別說什麼? - 只管走!
What? Don't say what? Just go!
老天 哪兒跟哪兒? 艾略特  哪兒跟哪兒?
Jesus Christ, what was that? Elliot, what was that?
送葬人 拜拜...
The Bye Bye Man. Bye Bye...
拜拜? 那什麼意思? 拜拜?
Bye Bye? What is that? Bye Bye?
你說什麼?
What is it, what are you saying?
拜拜什麼?
Bye Bye what?
那什麼? 艾略特? 拜拜什麼?
What is that? Elliot? Bye Bye what?
我很愛你們
I love you so much
艾略特!
Elliot!
愛麗絲
Alice
愛麗絲? 愛麗絲!
Alice? Alice!
愛麗絲?
Alice?
你在哪裡 寶貝
Where are you, baby?
愛麗絲!
Alice!
愛麗絲? 愛麗絲?
Alice? Alice?
甜心
Honey?
愛麗絲?
Alice?
愛麗絲!
Alice!
甜心! 過來!
Honey! Come here!
我冷死了
I was cold!
知道了 甜心 你嚇死我了
Oh, I know, honey, but you scared me so much!
不 看啊
Oh, no! Look!
艾略特小叔!
Uncle Elliot!
沒什麼
It's okay
火已經傷不到他了
The fire can't hurt him anymore
那孩子開車壓過了圖書館理員
So, this boy ran a librarian over,
殺害分屍了她的孩子
mutilated and murdered her children,
殺了室友們和自己
and then killed his roommates and himself
他本該今天被拘留的 卻被你們放了?
and you had him in custody today, but you let him go?
對 這可不是某個愣頭青犯下
"哥倫拜恩高中校園槍擊事件"
Yes. But this is not some creepy kid pulling a Columbine, okay?
我和他談過
I talked to him
事有蹊蹺 我有感覺
Something is going on here. I can feel it
我想去告別
I wanted to say goodbye
我知道 寶貝 我也想
I know, baby. Me, too
起碼把硬幣還給他
At least he gave me the coins
你說什麼
What are you talking about?
一定是他留在外面的 便於我找到
He must've left them out there for me to find
留在哪裡的外面 甜心
Left them out where, honey?
那張小桌子裡
In the little table
屋外 靠近垃圾桶那裡
Outside, next to the trash cans
桌子裡還有其他東西嗎
Well, was there anything else in this table?
沒有
No
有些文字
Just some writing
文字
Writing?
都寫了什麼
What did this writing say?
爸爸 這麼黑我怎麼看得見啊
Daddy. You know I can't read in the dark
你以為我是什麼啊?手電筒嗎
What do you think I am? A flashlight?
還有一個活著
We got one alive!
給我工具 縫合線 還有嗎啡
Get me a tool, a line and morphine!
等等  他有話要說
Wait, wait! He's trying to say something!
我聽著呢 說吧
Hey, I'm listening, go ahead
沒什麼
It won't matter
沒關係
It does matter
OK 慢慢來
Okay, take your time
沒事 我在這裡
It's okay. I'm here
我想知道
And I want to know
請告訴我
Please. Please tell me
送葬人...
Bye Bye Man...
*小眾電影_微博@電燈泡diandp 原創翻譯*
*艾略特 1992年 約翰*
*送葬人*